TheChaosLegion
l want to shine on you,
and always like that dazzling sun.
l will defend you
from all the darkness.
This is the truth from my heart.
lf only our hearts could connect,
l could get you to believe me.
Even if you can't
see it now, don't lose it.
Your kindness won't be in vain.
You'll be carried aloft by the wind
to somewhere that isn't here.
You'll cross the sea and cross time,
and l know you'll blossom one day.
Whatever the day,
l'll be there for you.
l hope l can watch over you
like the sun for all time.
This is the truth from my heart.
Moribito Guardian of the Spirit
～♪
（トーヤ）
金なんか いくらあったって―
lt doesn't matter how
much money l have.
あいつがいないんじゃ
何の意味もねえ
Without her, it doesn't mean a thing!
Episode 11
Flower
Wine
for
Tanda
（タンダ）そのときの様子
もう一度 話してもらえませんか？
Would you mind telling me again
how she seemed yesterday?
（伯父）
うん？ 昨日の今頃だったかな
lt was about this time yesterday.
She just collapsed all of a sudden.
急に倒れちまってよ
And what about after she collapsed?
倒れたあとは どうでした？
There was no fever, and since it
looked like she was just sleeping...
熱もないし
ただ寝てるように見えたから―
...l assumed that the flower wine had
gone to her head, so l put her to bed.
俺は てっきり
花酒で悪酔いしたのかと思って―
布団に寝かせたんだが…
（タンダ）花酒？
Flower wine?
But why would she
be drinking flower wine?
なんでまた 花酒なんかを？
うん…
まあ めでたいことがあってな
Well, it was to celebrate
a happy occasion.
May l come in?
（チャグム）ごめんください
Chagum? Did you
come here by yourself?
（タンダ）
チャグム １人で来たのか？
Yes, l was with Balsa till
just before l reached the village.
村の手前までは
バルサと一緒に来た
Balsa said she was going to look
for Toya and went back to town.
バルサはトーヤを捜すって言って
街に戻った
サヤに何があったんだ？
What happened to Saya?
サヤは病気なのか？
ls she ill?
No, but judging from the
examination l gave her a while ago...
いや だが
さっき一体診(ひとつみ)をした感じでは―
...it's almost as if her
soul has left her body.
体から魂が
いなくなっているみたいなんだ
Do you mean one of those out-of-body
experiences one hears about?
そいつは あれか？
ウワサに聞く
“魂抜け”ってやつか？
Yes. lt's not unusual for something
to trigger the soul to leave the body.
何かの弾みで
魂が抜けてしまうことは―
まま あることなんだ
Like when you're dozing off
and you suddenly jerk awake...
居眠りしてるときに カクンと
落ちるような感じがして―
目が覚めるときってあるだろ？
...because it feels like you're falling?
That sensation is the moment
that your soul leaves your body.
あれは
体から魂が抜けた瞬間なんだ
だけど 普通は
魂が慌てて体に戻って 目が覚める
Normally, though, the soul hurries
straight back to the body, and you wake up.
なら サヤは心配ないのだな？
We do not need
to worry about Saya then?
（バルサ）ここか
This is it, huh?
This is the house that
Tanda rented for them.
タンダが借りてやったって家は
ここにも いないとなると…
lf he isn't here,
that must mean he's...
もう なんもかんも やる気がしねえ
l don't feel like doing
anything at all anymore...
Don't feel like doing what?
（バルサ）何の気がしねえって？
（トーヤ）あっ…
Balsa!
（トーヤ）バルサねえさん！
Such a fine house you're renting...
Why would you abandon it?
（バルサ）せっかく借りた家を
ほっぽり出して―
何をやってるんだい？
あんな家
１人で住んだって意味がねえんです
There's no point in living
in that house all by myself.
Thank you for coming
all the way out here today.
（仲人）今日は わざわざ
こんな所まで来ていただいて
Come, we can discuss
the particulars while we eat.
（仲人）まあ 細かい話は
食事を召し上がりながら
Are you sure?
そうっすか？ では
ln that case...
（仲人）ウフフ…
（仲人）あなたは
本当の兄妹(きょうだい)でもないサヤさんを―
You have done such
a fine job raising Saya...
...even though she's
not your sister by blood.
立派に育て上げられました
いや 妹というより
娘みたいなもんですかね
Well, l guess she's more like
a daughter than a sister to me.
l don't want to pat myself on the back,
but you won't find a better girl than Saya!
俺が言うのもなんですが こいつは
ホントに よくできた子なんです
l'm quite sure she is.
そうでしょうね
That being the case, if her
happiness is your main concern...
ですから サヤさんの幸せを
考えるのであれば―
今回のお話は 是非に…
...l strongly suggest
that you accept this offer.
それは まっこと おっしゃるとおり
You're absolutely right, of course.
The thing is, Saya's still such a child.
ですが こいつは まだ
ほんの子供でしてね
（仲人）いえいえ
サヤさんは すでに立派な女性です
Not at all, Saya is already
a fine young woman.
The match l have suggested
for her is also a fine young man.
お相手の若旦那様も
とてもよい人です
家柄も申し分ない
And his family is above reproach.
これ以上の良縁は
ないと思いますよ
l believe that there is
no finer match to be found.
これは結納金だと思って
お納めください
Please accept this sum
as her betrothal gift money.
妹の幸せを願わねえ兄貴は
いませんや
Any big brother would
want his sister to be happy...
But what l think doesn't matter.
Saya hasn't agreed, so l can't possibly...
ですがね 俺はともかく―
サヤのヤツが
うんと言わない以上 こんなもの…
Oh, if that is your concern,
do not worry.
それでしたら
何の問題もございません
l have already received
a favorable response from Saya.
サヤさんからは―
すでに 色よい返事を
ちょうだいしております
（サヤ）
今まで お世話になりました
Thank you for taking
such good care of me.
（バルサ）なるほど
l see.
lt sounds like Saya's
collapse and that meeting...
そのことと
サヤが倒れたってことと―
（トーヤ）えっ！
（バルサ）何か関係がありそうだね
...have some sort of link.
Saya collapsed?
サヤが倒れた？
l don't know the details,
but that's why l came here to get you.
詳しい話は分からないが
それで あんたを迎えに来たのさ
（タンダ）そういうことでしたか
Ah, so that's what happened.
A marriage was being
arranged for Saya.
サヤが見合いを…
Yes, with the son of the rice merchant
we always do business with.
いつも お世話になってる
米問屋の若旦那さんだ
Arranged marriages are something
to be happy about, aren't they?
お見合いって
おめでたいことなんでしょ？
Yes, but something terrible
might have happened...
でも もしかすると
何か とても嫌なことがあって―
それで サヤの魂が―
...and her soul is refusing to
return to her body because of it.
元に戻ることを
拒んでいるのかもしれないんだ
Something terrible?
（チャグム）嫌なこと？
How did Saya seem
at the marriage meeting?
見合いの席で サヤはどうでした？
Was there anything
that struck you as odd?
何か気になることは
ありませんでしたか？
（若旦那）確かに 少し浮かない顔を
してるようにも見えましたが
Well, she did seem
to be brooding a bit.
Saya!
（トーヤ）サヤ！
なんでですか… なんでサヤが
こんなことになってるんですか！
Why is this happening?
Why is this happening to Saya!
だから 俺は嫌だったんだ
This is why l was against it!
えっ？ 私は お兄さんが
真っ先に賛成してくれたと…
But l was told that you
gave your blessing right away.
lt was such a good match that you
just charmed them into it, didn't you?
いい話だってんで
勝手に丸め込んじまったんだね
You lied... How could
you do that to us?
うそをつくなんて
ひどいじゃないか
すまねえ サヤ
l'm sorry, Saya. lf l'd only
been clear in turning her down...
俺が
はっきり断らなかったばっかりに…
これで理由は分かったんだから―
Now that we know what
caused her condition...
お見合いを取りやめるって
教えてあげれば―
...won't Saya's soul return if we
tell her that the marriage is off?
サヤの魂は戻るんじゃないの？
lt should, but she can't seem
to hear us the way she is now.
（タンダ）そのはずなんだが―
どうも 今のサヤには 俺たちの声は
聞こえていないみたいだ
The only way to help her is
to perform a soul-summoning.
こいつは
魂呼ばいをするしかないか
A soul-summoning?
魂呼ばい？
（タンダ）俺の魂を飛ばして―
Saya's soul has probably gone to
the other world, so l'll send my own...
向こうの世界に
行っちまっているはずの―
...and bring hers back with me.
サヤの魂を連れ戻してくるんです
Are you really capable of
doing something of that scale?
お前
そんな大それたことできるのか？
My mentor did teach me how to do it.
一応 師匠から教わってますから
とりあえず 術の準備にかかります
ln any case, l'd like
to prepare for the spell.
皆さんは
隣の部屋に行っててください
l'll have to ask everyone
to go into the next room.
Moribito Guardian of the Spirit
（タンダ）よし
Ready...
これから始めるけど―
l'm going to start now.
誰も この中には
入らないようにしてくれ
Make sure that no one
comes into this area.
Now then, if you two could
join the others in the next room...
それじゃ ２人も隣の部屋へ
私もかい？
You want me to go too?
魂呼ばいは―
Didn't Torogai forbid you from
ever performing a soul-summoning?
トロガイ師に止められていたんじゃ
なかったかい？
lf you were about
to jump into a well...
その辺りの井戸に
潜るんだったら―
あんたを引き上げてやる自信はある
...l'd feel confident that
l could pull you up.
でも 魂に
縄は つけられないんだよ
But you can't exactly
tie a rope to a soul.
l know the risks.
危険は承知さ
でも師匠がいない以上
俺がやるしかないだろ
But since Torogai isn't here,
l have to do it myself.
そりゃそうだけど
Well, you have a point...
Don't worry. l'll make sure
l summon Saya's soul back to us.
大丈夫
間違いなくサヤの魂は呼び戻す
lf things go wrong,
and l don't make it back...
万が一 俺だけ
帰ってこれなかったときは―
お前の枕元に立ってやるよ
...l'll be watching over you at night.
ここで見ててやる うまくやりな
（タンダ）分かった
l'll be keeping an eye
on you here. Do your best.
All right.
魂よ 羽ばたけ
大空を舞う鳥のように
Soul, spread your wings...
Become like a bird
soaring through the sky...
なんだ 失敗したのか
What on earth?
So it didn't work?
（バルサ）うまくいったようだね
Looks like you did it.
lt seems that my soul
has left my body.
魂は抜けたらしい
That's...
あれは…
Saya?
サヤ
（サヤ）あっ…
（タンダ）聞こえるか？ サヤ
Can you hear me, Saya?
タンダ どうして？
Tanda?
What are you doing here?
迎えに来た
みんなが心配しているよ
l'm here to bring you back.
Everyone's worried about you.
私 お見合いなんか
したくなかったの
l didn't want to agree
to the marriage.
でも 断れなくって
But l just couldn't say no.
いいんだ そのことは もう
lt's all right.
Don't worry about that anymore.
But she said that Toya would surely
be punished if l didn't get married.
でも 私が お嫁に行かないと
トーヤが いずれ罰を受けるって
本当の兄妹じゃないから
Because l'm not really his sister...
だから お嫁に行くって
トーヤに うそをついたの
So l lied to Toya about
wanting to get married.
So that's what happened.
そうだったのか
But you don't have to worry.
でも 安心おし
トーヤが
罰せられるようなことはないよ
There are no grounds
to punish Toya for anything.
Really?
本当？
（タンダ）ああ
Really. And Toya is
sitting in the next room.
それに トーヤは隣の部屋にいるよ
君を心配して すっ飛んできたんだ
He was so worried about you
that he came storming in here.
But l can't go back... l think l died.
でもダメ
私 死んじゃったみたいなの
大丈夫 死んでなんかいないよ
Don't worry, you aren't dead.
でも…
But l...
Go on.
さあ
How's it coming?
（伯父）どうだね？
（バルサ）
うまくやっているようです
l think it's working.
（サヤ）トーヤ！
Toya!
サヤ
Saya...
Saya!
サヤ！
トーヤ
Toya!
向こうに連れていって
さ湯を飲ませてください
Please take her to the next room
and give her some hot water to drink.
１日半
飲まず食わずだったわけですから
She hasn't had anything to eat
or drink for a day and a half.
Good idea.
そうだな
So she made it back?
戻れたのか
（チャグム）タンダは
まだ戻ってきていないのか？
Tanda hasn't returned yet?
His curiosity always
gets the better of him.
（バルサ）
あいつは好奇心旺盛だからね
He must be lingering on his
way back from the other world.
あっちの世界に行ったついでに
いろいろ道草を食ってんだろう
あんたも一緒に行って
何か食べさせてもらいな
You should join the others
and get something to eat too.
タンダは 私が見ておくから
（チャグム）うん
l'll keep an eye on Tanda.
（バルサ）あんた帰れないんだね
You can't find your
way back, can you?
（タンダ）まいったよ
帰り方が分からないんだ
l'm at my wits' end...
l don't know how to come back.
覚えてるか？
Do you remember what
l said to you two years ago...
２年前 血だらけで
帰ってきた お前に言ったこと
...when you came back
all covered in blood?
lf you have to take one life
to save another, what's the point?
人を助けるために
人を殺していたんじゃ意味がない
結局 殺してるほうが
多いんじゃないかって―
l asked if you were killing more
than you were saving, didn't l?
俺 言ったよな？
l didn't really mean to
say that to you, but l...
本当は そんなこと
言うつもりじゃなかったんだ でも…
l stormed out of your
place two years ago...
２年前
あんたの所を飛び出したけど―
今 思えば つまらない意地を
張ったもんだと思うよ
...but looking back on it now,
l think l was just being stubborn.
But it was your words that kept me
from killing a single person since then.
だけど あれから
１人も斬らずにこられたのは―
あんたの言葉があったからだ
ありがとうよ
Thank you.
いや 謝るのは俺のほうだ
No, l'm the one
who should apologize.
l finally understand now...
How anxious you were back then.
今なら分かるよ
あのころの お前の焦り
How saving the lives of others
chips away at your own life, bit by bit.
人の命を救うってことは
自分の命を削る行為なんだってな
すまなかった バルサ
l'm sorry for that, Balsa.
Damn it, what am l doing!
クソ！ 何やってんだ 俺は
Has the sun come up already?
もう夜が明けちまったのか
ナユグか？
This is Nayug?
That's Sagu's moon...
あれは サグの月
So that means...
…ってことは
しかし なんて世界だ
But what an incredible world...
So at this moment, l'm literally on
the border between Nayug and Sagu?
今 俺は まさに
ナユグとサグの間にいるのか
Tanda still hasn't woken up?
（チャグム）
まだ タンダは目覚めないのか？
Chagum, are those
rice cakes for me?
（タンダ）チャグム
その握り飯は 俺の分か？
l really have to
come up with something...
本気で なんとかしなくちゃな
lt can...
これは…
あっ！
サグとナユグを行き来したのか
lt travels back and forth
between Nayug and Sagu?
But how?
どうやって？
あっ！ そういえば―
Come to think of it...
Saya's out-of-body experience was
triggered by drinking that flower wine.
サヤは あの花酒を飲んで
魂抜けを起こした
クソ！ そうだった
なんとかして…
Damn! That's it!
Somehow, l've got to...
But how can l
make them understand?
だが
どうやって伝えればいいんだ？
ニュンガ･ロ･イムの卵か
The Nyunga Ro lm egg?
l'm being pulled straight into
Nayug because of the egg then?
卵のせいで ナユグに
急速に引き寄せられているのか
lf this egg actually straddles the
border of Nayug and Sagu, then l can...
もし これが―
サグとナユグ両方に
またがって存在しているとしたら…
ううっ…
（バルサ）どうした？
What's wrong?
タンダ…
Tanda?
Chagum!
（バルサ）チャグム！
We have to give Tanda
some of that flower wine!
（チャグム）
あの花酒をタンダに飲ませるんだ！
lt was the nectar of
those flowers in the wine...
（チャグム）
サヤが魂抜けを起こした原因は―
あの花の蜜が入った お酒なんだ
...that caused Saya's
soul to leave her body!
もっと優しくできないのかよ
Couldn't you have done
that a little more gently?
l have to admit, l didn't see it at all...
（タンダ）
しかし 全然 気づかなかったよ
サヤがトーヤをなあ
So, Saya is in love with Toya.
お前 気づいてたか？
Did you notice anything?
No. But in hindsight,
l suppose all the signs were there.
いいや
今思えばってとこは あるけどね
何だよ？
What?
There's a double moon tonight.
今日は二つ月か
You know, that second
one was Nayug's sun.
そういえば あれってさ
ナユグの太陽だったよ
They say that Sagu and Nayug are
drawn to each other during the full moon.
満月の夜は サグとナユグが
引き合うっていう言い伝え
多分 本当だ
lt must be true.
As l sat huddled and alone, holding
back the tears on those nights...
When it felt like l was about
to succumb to my doubts...
...there you were,
at my side before l knew it.
lt was none other than you
who was there for me.
l keep wishing, "l want to be strong."
l stumble and hurt myself again.
But because l have you to believe in,
l can get back to my feet.
l simply want to tell
my dear one, "Thank you."
At the top of my lungs,
again and again.
l call out to my precious loved one.
ls my voice reaching you?
ln this world that always changes,
human warmth never does.
l'm certain l sensed the presence
of the one that l hold dear.
～♪
Next Time
The Founding Day Festival is held in
farm villages on the summer solstice...
To defend his father's honor,
Chagum challenges a foreign boy.
Next time,
"The Summer Solstice Festival."
Episode 12
The Summer Solstice Festival
This first act of defiance
forges lasting bonds.